<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Evelyn Uuemaa&#39;s Maps</title>
    <link>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Evelyn Uuemaa&#39;s Maps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to create a paper-cut style map</title>
      <link>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/post/paper_cut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/post/paper_cut/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where the paper cut style originates but I guess it has been around in the design world already long time. However, likely one of the first GIS-approaches was done by John Nelson with ArcPro. This is also available as style for ArcPro. However, I aimed to create the same style with QGIS and the mapping theme was inspired by the beautiful snow this winter in Estonia.
For input data you would need any numerical point data (rain, temperature, snow etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create Tanaka contours</title>
      <link>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/post/tanaka_contours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/post/tanaka_contours/</guid>
      <description>Tanaka contours aka illuminated contours is terrain visualization method developed first by Prof. Tanaka Kitirito in 1950. The mimics 3D by illuminating the northwestern slopes and shading the opposite slopes. I followed Anita Graser&amp;rsquo;s tutorial to create Tanaka contours and updated it a bit as QGIS has evolved since then. Her tutorial was inspired by Hannes Kröger&amp;rsquo;s attempt to create the effect using QGIS.
You need a DEM for creating Tanaka contours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/about/</guid>
      <description>About I&amp;rsquo;m a geographer by heart and by education. Currenty, I&amp;rsquo;m Assoc. Professor in Geoinformatics and Head of Department of Geography at University of Tartu, Estonia. I hold a PhD in landscape ecology and environmental protection and my research interests evolve around the interactions of land use/land cover and water quality, landscape changes and geospatial modelling with machine learning. My special interests are geospatial visualisation and map design. I&amp;rsquo;m always keen on trying new visualisation methods and especially with the focus on making maps nice fast with open-source software like QGIS and Blender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevelyn1.github.io/mapcrastinating/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact Interested in collaboration or want to ask something? Contact me via LinkedIn or Twitter</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
